Euan McKay – Resume

3D Artist & Software Developer

Personal Statement:

I am a highly motivated and enthusiastic software developer, 3D artist, and honours computer science graduate. I have been involved in a range of projects: 3D graphics for award-winning games, 3D graphics and programming for indie games, the creation of web apps for museums and have been involved in game jams.

I am knowledgeable about the industry and proficient with a wide range of industry-standard software, and have a knack for learning new tools and workflows quickly. I am a firm believer that a multidisciplinary set of skills produces the best results and I have experience in: programming, 3D graphics, web development, game development, AI & databases.

Since I first started working in games I have been dedicated to not just meeting a brief, but lighting a spark in users & clients.

Qualifications:

Heriot-Watt University – BSC Computer Science – Edinburgh (2018):

Honours: Graduated with 1st class honours; winner of the Walker-Cooper prize; Winner of the deputy principals prize.

Dissertation: I was awarded an A grade and the Walker-Cooper prize for my dissertation on procedural level generation. The finished dissertation successfully produced a configurable tool in Unity & C# which would produce procedural levels and functional mini-maps given a set of tiles. <u>Link to dissertation report.</u>

Notable Courses:

- 3rd Year Project:: I received an A grade for my group project in my 3rd year. This project revolved around producing a resource allocation system for IT companies. The produced system allowed the user to organize staff by using a web-based application with server-side functionality. For the system, the group also produced a marketing website, robust back end and full documentation.
- 3D Graphics Course: In my final year I took a comprehensive graphics course which taught me how to create and implement a graphics pipeline, shaders and rendering engine using OpenGL and C++.
- Other courses taken include: Discrete Maths, Games Programming, Data Mining, Big Data, Web Design, Al and Language Processing.

Skills:

Programming Languages:

C, C#,C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, SML, openGL, PDDL.

Web & Database Development:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL.

Graphics Skills:

3D modelling, Rendering, Texturing, UV mapping, Rigging, Retopology, Lighting.

Graphics Technologies:

Maya, Blender, Eevee, Arnold, Substance Painter, Substance Designer, Zbrush, Photoshop, Marvellous Designer, Marmoset Toolbag, Unity, Unreal Engine.

Experience:

DayBreak Games (2015 – present)

Contract Artist - Planetside 2:

- Worked with the producer and art department to create a set of cosmetic items for 'Planetside 2'. These Items were shipped on time and up to standard.
- The created cosmetic Items were developed for an upcoming faction and had to meet both aesthetic and technical qualities.

FreeLance Artist - Planetside 2:

- Produced over 50 cosmetic items for sale in the cash shop of 'Planetside 2'. These items had to both meet the games strict technical requirements, as well as having to fit the games aesthetic and meet the art directors standards. Items created include helmets, aircraft, full characters. and vehicles.
- Helped expand the categories of the cash shop in 'Planetside 2' by opening up successful categories such as 'aircraft cosmetics' to their 'PlayerStudio' program.
- Helped budding freelance artists within the 'PlayerStudio' program with learning 3D modelling and texturing. From Q&A, live streams or producing tutorial videos.
- Worked on commission for players to produce custom content for 'Planetside 2'.
- Used proprietary tools to prepare cosmetic items for the game.

St Cecilia's Hall (2019)

Application Developer:

- Worked with the museum directors and masters students to develop a web-based application for the museum.
- The application is a web-based interface that would allow users to play audio clips guiding users around the museum's collection, as well as playing audio clips from the museum's instruments.

Edinburgh Business Weekend (2016-2017)

Senior Technology and Web Manager:

- Met regularly with the president of the Edinburgh business weekend (EBW) to update and revamp their website, and manage the online applications and processing for the 2016 and 2017 EBW events.
- Maintained the EBW website and helped streamline and clear up websites source files.

Global Game Jam 2019: Heriot-Watt Team (2019)

Artist and Level Designer:

- Worked with a university team to compete in 'global game jam 2019'.
- Over the course of 48 hours, I produced a wide range of props and characters for my team's entry in the jam, and
 was responsible for a large section of as well as working on rigging and assisting other team members with
 programming.

NoSense Games (2018-present)

Lead Artist, level designer and programmer – MechaMania:

- Lead artist in charge of producing a wide range of assets, hard-surface characters and environments.
- Due to the projects nature I have worked on a range of artistic elements from environments, lighting, rigging, UI, modelling and texturing.
- Co-developer working on a range of programming tasks from character interactions to UI programming.
- Worked with the lead programmer to tackle artistic and code-based challenges of developing a phsyics based games over networks.

Contact:

Email: EuanEdwardMcKay@Gmail.com

Phone: 07593113970 Website: McKay3d.co.uk

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/euan-mckay-8962a3128/

Artstation: https://www.artstation.com/euanmckay